export default data5 = [
    {
        id: "q1",
        question: "Who made the first coins to be minted in Britain?",
        options: ["The people of the Stone Age", "The Anglo-saxons", "The people of the Iron Age", "The Romans"],
        correct_option: "The people of the Iron Age"
    },
    {
        id: "q2",
        question: "Who built the Tower of London?",
        options: ["William the Conqueror", "Queen Victoria", "Queen Elizabeth I", "Oliver Cromwell"],
        correct_option: "William the Conqueror"
    },
    {
        id: "q3",
        question: "There are 15 national parks in England, Wales and Scotland. What are national parks?",
        options: ["Giant greenhouses", "Land formations of columns made from volcanic lava", "Areas of protected countryside", "Medieval buildings"],
        correct_option: "Areas of protected countryside"
    },
    {
        id: "q4",
        question: "How often are ‘Prime Minister’s Questions’ held in the parliament?",
        options: ["Every day", "Every week", "Every two weeks", "Once a month"],
        correct_option: "Every week"
    },
    {
        id: "q5",
        question: "Which king was executed in 1649?",
        options: ["James I", "Charles II", "James VII", "Charles I"],
        correct_option: "Charles I"
    },
    {
        id: "q6",
        question: "Where was William Shakespeare born?",
        options: ["Manchester", "Oldham", "Stratford-upon-Avon", "Lincolnshire"],
        correct_option: "Stratford-upon-Avon"
    },
    {
        id: "q7",
        question: "Who was reigning in England when English settlers first began to colonise the eastern coast of America?",
        options: ["Queen Victoria", "Henry VIII", "Elizabeth I", "Charles II"],
        correct_option: "Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        id: "q8",
        question: "Scotland and Wales use a system called ‘individual registration’ where all those entitled to vote must complete their own registration form.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correct_option: "False"
    },
    {
        id: "q9",
        question: "On what day is the birth of Jesus Christ celebrated?",
        options: ["Father’s Day", "Christmas Day", "New Year", "Boxing Day"],
        correct_option: "Christmas Day"
    },
    {
        id: "q10",
        question: "What sort of battle was the ‘Battle of Britain’, fought between Germany and Britain in the summer of 1940?",
        options: ["A battle in the sea", "An aerial battle", "A battle in the mountains", "A battle without rifles"],
        correct_option: "An aerial battle"
    },
    {
        id: "q11",
        question: "Where is Swansea located?",
        options: ["England", "Northern Ireland", "Scotland", "Wales"],
        correct_option: "Wales"
    },
    {
        id: "q12",
        question: "Who established the Church of England?",
        options: ["Henry VIII", "Oliver Cromwell", "Winston Churchill", "William of Orange"],
        correct_option: "Henry VIII"
    },
    {
        id: "q13",
        question: "In 1348, one third of the population in England, Wales and Scotland died as a result of which disease?",
        options: ["Measles", "Leprosy", "Smallpox", "The Black Death"],
        correct_option: "The Black Death"
    },
    {
        id: "q14",
        question: "Haggis is a traditional food from which area?",
        options: ["Wales", "England", "Northern Ireland", "Scotland"],
        correct_option: "Scotland"
    },
    {
        id: "q15",
        question: "Which court deals with minor criminal offences in Scotland?",
        options: ["The Sheriff Court", "The Magistrates' Court", "The Crown Court", "The Justice of the Peace Court"],
        correct_option: "The Justice of the Peace Court"
    },
    {
        id: "q16",
        question: "What is the minimum age required for a citizen to stand for public office?",
        options: ["16", "18", "21", "25"],
        correct_option: "18"
    },
    {
        id: "q17",
        question: "Who makes sure that the opposition has a guaranteed amount of time to debate issues which it chooses during political debates?",
        options: ["The shadow cabinet", "The Speaker", "The Queen", "Nobody"],
        correct_option: "The Speaker"
    },
    {
        id: "q18",
        question: "Which British Prime Minister nationalized major industries including coal and steel?",
        options: ["Harold Macmillan", "Clement Attlee", "John Major", "Sir Alec Douglas-Home"],
        correct_option: "Clement Attlee"
    },
    {
        id: "q19",
        question: "Who was the first Archbishop of Canterbury?",
        options: ["St Augustine", "St Columba", "St Andrew", "Kenneth MacAlpin"],
        correct_option: "St Augustine"
    },
    {
        id: "q20",
        question: "What name is given to the clock tower at the Houses of Parliament in honour of Queen Elizabeth II’s Diamond Jubilee in 2012?",
        options: ["Big Ben", "Big Clock", "Elizabeth Tower", "Clock Tower"],
        correct_option: "Elizabeth Tower"
    },
    {
        id: "q21",
        question: "Whose details are NOT listed in the Phone Book nor in the Yellow Pages?",
        options: ["The Queen", "MEPs", "MPs, Assembly members", "All of the above"],
        correct_option: "The Queen"
    },
    {
        id: "q22",
        question: "Which of the following words comes from the Norman French?",
        options: ["Apple", "Beauty", "Cow", "Summer"],
        correct_option: "Beauty"
    },
    {
        id: "q23",
        question: "How are the official reports where the Parliament’s proceedings are published called?",
        options: ["Domesday Book", "Hansard", "Parliamentary reports", "Carta Magna"],
        correct_option: "Hansard"
    },
    {
        id: "q24",
        question: "How many Assembly members does the National Assembly for Wales have? ",
        options: ["40", "70", "50", "60"],
        correct_option: "60"
    }
]